

export const data = [
    {
      question: "What is Availability Zone?",
      answer:"An Availability Zone is a single data center or a group of data centers within a Region.",
    },
    {
      question:"What is an Edge location?",
      answer:"An edge location is a site that Amazon CloudFront(Content Delivery Network) uses to store cached copies of your content closer to your customers for faster delivery.",
    },
    
    
    {
      question:"Factors to choose Global regions?",
      answer:"The four important factors are Compliance, Proximity, Feature availability, Pricing.",
    },
    {
      question:"What is AWS outpost?",
      answer:"AWS Outposts is a fully managed service that extends AWS infrastructure, services, APIs, and tools to customer or client's premises.",
    },
    {
      question: "Tools for provisioning AWS resources?",
      answer:"The tools used are AWS management console, AWS command line interface and Software development kits. Other tools are AWS Elastic Beanstalk and AWS CLoudFormation.",
    },
    {
      question: "What is AWS Elatic Beanstalk?",
      answer:"It provisions AWS resources for the client and automates all the services. client just needs to provide the code and configuration settings. Load balancing, scaling, adjusting capacity is done for client by AWS Elatic Beanstalk.",
    },
    {
      question: "What is AWS Virtual Private Cloud(VPC)?",
      answer:"It is a networking service by AWS that helps to create an islolated virtual private network and provides secure connections, screens traffic for multiple AWS services requests and restricts instance access inside your virtual network."
    },
    {
      question: "What are subnets in VPC?",
      answer:"Subnets are chunks of IP addresses in your VPC that allow you to group different AWS resources based on security or operational needs. Subnets decide whether resources are publically or privately available."   
    },
    {
      question: "What is Internet gateway in VPC?",
      answer:"An internet gateway is a connection between a virtual private network and the private network(such as on-pemise data center or corporate internal network).Without an internet gateway, no one can access the resources within your VPC.The virtual private gateway is the component that allows protected internet traffic to enter into the VPC."   
    },
    {
      question: "What is AWS Direct Connect?",
      answer:"It provides direct connection between VPN and your private network ."   
    },
    {
      question: "What is Public Subnet",
      answer:"Public subnets contain resources that need to be accessible by the public, such as an online store's website."   
    },
    {
      question: "What is Private Subnet",
      answer:"Private subnets contain resources that should be accessible only through your private network, such as a database that contains customers' personal information and order histories."   
    },
    {
      question: "What is Network Access Control List(ACL)",
      answer:"A network access control list (ACL) is a virtual firewall that controls inbound and outbound traffic at the subnet level.These perform Stateless packet filtering.They remember nothing and check packets that cross the subnet border each way: inbound and outbound."   
    },
    {
      question: "What is Security group?",
      answer:"A security group is a virtual firewall that controls inbound and outbound traffic for an Amazon EC2 instance.It is a component of VPC that checks packet permissions.These perform Stateful packet filtering."   
    },






]

































